Finding Aid for the Library Special Collections (LSC) departmental decor collection Internal.001
UCLA Library Special Collections
Library Special Collections (LSC) departmental decor collection
1960-2021
UCLA Library Special Collections
Internal.001
51 linear feet
Scope and Contents
The Library Special Collections (LSC) departmental decor collection contains materials which range from A.D. 79 through 2013. The collection consists of 48 framed artworks which were either purchased by the department, donated to the department, or reproduced from the department's holdings for the purpose of work space decoration. These artworks include posters, letterpress creations, photographs, paintings, a map, photogenic drawings, serigraphs, a panorama print, photographic reproductions, and a Festina Lente piece which contains a silver denarius. The majority of these artworks were purchased by Victoria Steele between 2000-2009 during her tenure as head of Special Collections while the department received the majority of its letterpress artworks in 1997 from James Davis when he retired as Rare Books Librarian from Special Collections.
- Roget's photograph by Cara Barer, undated
- La Bruja photograph by Cara Barer, 2008
- Untitled photograph by Cara Barer, undated
- Whirligig photograph by Cara Barer, undated
- What Can a Woman Do? photograph by Cara Barer, undated
- Earth Vegetation / 08-7 photogenic drawing by Carol Panaro-Smith and James Hajicek, 2008
- Sunflowers photogenic drawing by Carol Panaro-Smith and James Hajicek, 2007
- Earth Vegetation / 08-03 photogenic drawing by Carol Panaro-Smith and James Hajicek, 2008
- Hotel Green panorama print, undated
- Picturing Childhood: Illustrated Children's Books from the University of California Collections 1550-1990 exhibition poster, 1997
- Patronato Nacional Del Turismo Malaga Clima Delicioso En Todo Tiempo poster by R. Verdugo Randi, undated
- Patronato Nacional Del Turismo Valencia Jardin De Espana poster by Imprenta Rivadeneyra, undated
- Patronato Nacional Del Turismo Marruecos Espanol Tetuan A Hora Y Media De Espana. Via Algeciras poster by M. Bertuchi, undated
- Patronato Nacional Del Turismo Huelva Cuna De America poster by J.Y.R. Diaz-Jara, undated
- Patronato Nacional Del Turismo Flores Y Frutas Del Mediterraneo poster by A. Vercher, undated
- Charles E. Young Research Library Department of Special Collections Sarah Whitman cover photographic reproduction, 2006
- Charles E. Young Research Library Department of Special Collections Margaret Armstrong covers photographic reproduction, 2006
- Charles E. Young Research Library Department of Special Collections Will Bradley cover photographic reproduction, 2006
- Charles E. Young Research Library Department of Special Collections Frank Hazen cover photographic reproduction, 2006
- UCLA Day poster, 1984 June 28
- MAMA full-color letterpress poster, undated
- Engraving Then & Now retrospective 50th Exhibition of The Society of Wood Engravers Black Bear Press limited print, 1988
- Folly or Saintliness, Jose Echegaray print by Lamson Wolfe and Co., undated
- Babar a 50 ans! poster by Laurent De Brunhoff, 1981
- Open To All Except the Censor letterpress poster, undated
- Berkeley Public Library poster by David Lance Gaines, 1974
- The Chap-Book Semi-Monthly poster, undated
- Gill Sans Hague and Gill poster by Skelton's Press Wellingborough, 1982 November
- The Curwen Press Ltd Unicorn poster by James Shurmer, undated
- The Myriade Press Standard Lay of the Case poster by Hermann Zapf, 1978
- A Bird's Eye View of The Whittington Press by Miriam Macgregor, 1987 April 19
- "Hey Fellows!" American Library Association United War Work Campaign poster by John Emmet Sheridan, undated
- Festina Lente Denarius, A.D. 79-96
- Catalina poster, undated
- Lascaux: Gold to airy thinness beat painting by Mary Heebner, undated
- Sierra Nevada Headquarters mixed media painting by Valerie P. Cohen, 2013
- Alice B. Toklas painting by Francis Rose, undated
- Castle painting by Scellon, 1980
- Cristobal Colon Asesinando a los Indios serigraph, edition 64 by Frank Romero, 1992
- The Arrest of the Paleteros serigraph by Frank Romero, 1996
- California, the year 'round poster, undated
- Los Angeles, California, 1894 map
- Helicopter hovering over the LA Civic Center with Chief Parker photograph, 1953
- Homage a Gertrude by Pablo Picasso framed facsimile, undated
- Japan -- Japanese Government Railways poster by Munetsugu Satomi, 1937
- Los Angeles -- Fly TWA Jets poster by David Klein, circa 1960s
- Fly TWA Los Angeles poster by David Klein, circa 1960s
- Los Angeles/American Airlines poster by Fred Ludekens, circa 1955